Guide to the Haim Reingold Papers, 1934-1978 RL.10186
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Haim Reingold papers
1934-1978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reingold, Haim
RL.10186
2 Linear Feet
Collection includes correspondence, grant proposals, teaching materials, and articles on and by Haim Reingold.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Historical note
Haim Reingold (1910-2003) was born in Poland, raised in Tel Aviv, and came to the United States in 1930, where he taught mathematics for almost 70 years. He received his bachelor's, master's, and doctorate in mathematics from the University of Cincinnati, and joined the faculty at the Illinois Institute of Technology in 1945.
Provenance
The Haim Reingold Papers were received as part of the Karl Menger Papers by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1995.
Collection Overview
The Haim Reingold Papers contain various correspondence, a number of grant proposals for his teacher training programs, professional service files, teaching and test materials, Reingold's 1938 dissertation, articles he wrote, and mentions of his name and work that he collected, as well as miscellaneous documents, some of which relate to his collaboration with his colleague, Karl Menger.
Related Materials
This collection was found with the Karl Menger Papers. There may be some overlap in the materials as there are a number of folders containing unidentified miscellaneous items.
Mathematicians -- United States; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- United States; Illinois Institute of Technology. Department of Mathematics; Menger, Karl, 1902-1985; Reingold, Haim
- Correspondence, 1940-1976; 1
  - Aginski, Henri, 1957-1969 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, H. W., 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Associate Dean, University of Illinois
  - Basic Mathematics for Science and Engineering, 1943-1957 (Box 1)
    Correspondence regarding Basic Mathematics for Science and Engineering.
  - Chicago Daily News, 1958-1970 (Box 1)
    Correspondence with Chicago Daily News. Includes clippings about judging for youth Silver Knight awards in mathematics.
  - Chicago Sun Times, 1967 (Box 1)
    Includes clipping.
  - Clarkson College of Technology, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    Includes pamphlet publications from Clarkson College.
  - F.E. Compton Company, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Cooper Union, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Crown Jewish Academy, 1970 (Box 1)
    Includes evaluation and evaluation materials.
  - Degani, Meir, 1955 (Box 1)
  - De La Salle Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    Includes information about the institute.
  - Everitt, W. L., 1956 (Box 1)
  - Follett College Book Co., 1974 (Box 1)
  - Guralnick, Sidney, 1975 (Box 1)
    Correspondence concerning Dr. Guralnick.
  - Hadoar Hebrew Weekly, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Jewish United Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Keiffer, Mildred, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Light, Israel, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Mehlberg, Henry, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Miser, Hugh, 1940-1967 (Box 1)
  - Motorola Communications Division, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Our Lady of Cincinnati College, 1945-1957 (Box 1)
  - Pearson, H.L., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Penn, Howard Lewis, undated (Box 1)
    Noted as the son-in-law of Harold Straus.
  - Pullman Standard, 1970 (Box 1)
    Notes and correspondence regarding mathematics refresher course taught by Haim Reingold for Pullman Standard.
  - Rudnianski, Kuba, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Schraut, Kenneth, 1956-1966 (Box 1)
  - Schechterman, A., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Wiley & Sons, Inc., Publishers, 1967 (Box 1)
    Correspondence and materials regarding the revision of Basic Mathematics.
  - Miscellaneous Letters to Industry, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, 1943-1975; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Personal correspondence of Haim Reingold. Contains letters, notes, cards, and postcards.
- Academia, 1934-1978; 2
  - NSF Proposal: Student Science Training, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    Rejected proposal and documents pertaining to it.
  - NSF Proposal: Pre-College Teacher Development, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Comprehensive Assistance to Undergraduate Science Education Proposal, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Trustee Dinner, 1965 (Box 2)
    Includes copies of speech prepared by Haim Reingold for the dinner.
  - NSF Material, 1972-1976 (Box 2)
    Illinois Institute of Technology past proposal materials.
  - Illinois Institute of Technology Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - NSF Proposal: For Minorities, 1978 (Box 2)
  - University of Illinois Salaries, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    Includes note from son, Edward, who obtained this list.
  - Science Research Associates: Questions for Test, 1958-1964 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence regarding payment, test questions, and copies of tests.
  - Science Research Associates: Test Materials, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Retirement Dinner for Haim Reingold, 1975 (Box 2)
    Includes correspondence, letters of congratulation, gift contributors, and other notes.
  - Publicity on Haim Reingold, 1943-1976; 5 folders (Box 2)
    Includes clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, and other documents.
  - Invariants of a System of Linear Homogeneous Differential Equations of Second Order, 1938 (Box 2)
    Dissertation.
  - Teaching Notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Pictures, 1968 and undated (Box 2)
    Some photographs are identified, many are not.
  - Reingold, Edward, 1961-1976 (Box 2)
    Notes, publications, and other documents from Haim Reingold's son, Edward.
  - Test Material, undated (Box 2)
  - Articles by Haim Reingold, 1934-1947 and undated (Box 2)
  - Notes, undated (Box 2)
    Helen Skala's work is included.
  - University of Illinois: Department of Computer Science Booklets, 1974 and undated (Box 2)
  - Goldfarb, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Files, undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
    Miscellaneous notes and other documents.